该起床了 快点 哥们 起床
Rise and shine! Come on, man, get up!
嘿 小子们 快起床
Oh, boy. Come on, get up!
今天上课 你们要迟到了
School day. Y'all gonna be late!
动起来 起床上学去
Let's go. Get up for school.
快 起来 快点 伙计
Go! Get up. Come on, man.
- 该死 Wallace - 骂也没用
- Damn, Wallace. - "Damn, Wallace," nothing!
你们都知道不去学校会怎样
Y'all know what happens if you don't go to school?
很快 他们就会找上门
Soon enough, they're gonna be calling
然后把你们全送进收养所
And all y'all gonna end up in foster care.
如果你们想进收养所 就继续把小黑屁股赖床上吧
If y'all want foster care, climb your little black asses back into bed.
别挡路 哥们 该死 现在做这事早了点吧
Get outta my way, man. Damn, it's too early for this shit.
缉毒警?
Narcos?
不 巡警
No, rollies.
嘿 早饭在哪?
Yo, where's breakfast at?
给你 再给你一份
Here, man. You get two.
- 我想要两袋 - 你只有一袋 快点
- I want two bags. - You don't get two. Come on,
真贪吃 拿上薯条
Getting greedy. Take the chips!
快点 拿好你的果汁
Come on. Take your juice.
快点 伙计
Come on, man.
我的呢
Where's mine?
找你老师去 快点 小子
Go show your teacher. Come on, man.
如果动物被困 请拨打396-6286
- 你的书包呢 - 老师没布置家庭作业
- Where's your book bag? - Teacher ain't giving no homework.
这是我见过最糟的自杀
That's the worst case of suicide I've ever seen.
是他
That's him.
你看见没?
You see?
是他 就在那
That's him, right there.
是Omar的小弟
That's Omar's boy.
火线重案组 第一季 第六集 监听
The Wire S01E06 The Wire
* When you walk through the garden *
* You gotta watch your back *
* Well I beg your pardon *
* Walk the straight and narrow track *
* If you walk with Jesus *
* He's gonna save your soul *
* You gotta keep the devil *
* Way down in the hole *
* All the angels sing *
* About Jesus' mighty sword *
* And they'll shield you with their wings *
* And keep you close to the lord *
* Don't pay heed to temptation *
* For his hands are so cold *
* You gotta help me keep the devil *
* Way down in the hole *
* way down in the hole *
细节决定成败  -- Freamon
我他妈的能跟他说什么
What the fuck can I tell him?
他想听什么 你就说什么 Jimmy
Whatever the man wants to hear, Jimmy.
我们的回头浪子
Prodigal son.
警长 我们有个不错的机会 破掉这几桩案子
Major, we got a good shot at clearing a couple of cases here.
- 一个是-- - 我们不谈案子
- One thing-- - We're not here to talk cases, McNulty.
我不关心你的案子 坐
I don't care about your cases. Sit.
放松
Relax.
我是个讲道理的人
I'm a reasonable guy.
事实上 我到哪人们都说:
In fact, everywhere I go, people say to me:
"Bill Rawls 你真他妈讲道理"
"Bill Rawls, you are a reasonable fucking guy."
我没说错吧 Jay?
Am I right, Jay?
你很讲道理 长官
You are reasonable, sir.
没错 是的 就是这样
Yes. Yes, I am.
你的警督知道我是个讲道理的人...
And because your sergeant knows me to be reasonable...
所以他几周前跑来 跟我讲道理 对吗 Jay?
He came in here a couple weeks ago and reasoned with me. Right, Jay?
我们理论了一番 确实如此
We reasoned. We did.
我们讨论的结果是尽管 有微不足道的爱尔兰血统...
We reasoned that despite his negligible lrish ancestry...
并且常常口不择言
And a propensity to talk out of turn,
Jimmy McNulty仍然算个好员工
Jimmy McNulty is a good worker.
也许值得一救
Probably worth saving.
- 警长 我不是-- - 一个帅小伙 嗯?
- Major, I'm not-- - He's a good-looking kid, huh?
你知道我们这是在干嘛吗 McNulty
Do you know what we do here, McNulty?
我们在干嘛
What we do here?
这算是一种....什么来着
That was one of them.... What is it?
这种问题你不需要...
A question you don't have to--
一个设问句
A rhetorical question.
您是在修辞  您会修辞 又讲道理 长官
You were being rhetorical. Rhetorical and reasonable, sir.
我们查谋杀案 按照先后
We work murder cases here, as they come in,
一次一件 这叫轮班
One at a fucking time. It's called a rotation.
你保持待命直到接一个案子 然后你调查取证
You're up till you catch one, then you step down,
解决这个案子... 其他人则跟上待命
Work it for a while... someone else steps up.
在一个每年发生250到300件案子的城里
It's a simple but effective way to do business in a town
这种方法简单有效
That has 250 to 300 cases a year.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
但如果有人想脱离轮班...
But if someone gets it into his head to leave the rotation...
这就给其他警员增加了负担 因为他们得接下他的工作
It puts an unfair burden on other detectives who have to pick up their casework.
过度工作的警察容易犯错
Overworked cops make mistakes.
而错误会降低整组的破案率
Mistakes lower the unit-wide clearance rate.
这就会让一些
And that can make someone who is
跟我一样讲道理的人变得...
Otherwise as reasonable as me....
不讲道理
Unreasonable.
McNulty探员
Detective McNulty,
我希望下周再见到你时...
I expect to see your ass back here next week...
你轮值到夜班
When your shift rotates to night work.
他今天起很早
He's up early today.
昨晚呼机也响了不少次
A lot of pager activity last night, too.
女人都用不了那么长时间
No woman takes that long.
是啊 但我看上去不错 对吧
Yeah. But I look good, right?
哇 全都是你做的?
Wow. You did all this?
煎了一两个蛋 算不了什么
Burned an egg or two. Ain't no thing.
是吗
Yeah?
我老妈总是说:
My mama always said:
"别让她们烧饭 一旦她们进了厨房..."
"Don't let them get to cooking. Once they're in the kitchen,
"你就只有把房子的钥匙给她们了"
"ain't nothing left to do but give 'em a key to your house."
我不要钥匙 不要房子
I don't want no key. I don't want no house.
你老妈也对我一无所知
And your mama don't know shit about me.
他长得很像你
Looks just like you.
对 长得很像
Yeah, he do.
他母亲呢
Where's his mother?
在附近
Around the way.
是吗 你们还是朋友?
Yeah. You friends?
你知道 她想要钥匙...
You know, she want a key...
她想要房子 想要车子
She want a house, she want a car,
要新衣服 项链...
She wants some new clothes, a necklace...
要零钱 要海边旅游
Some pocket change, a trip to the shore,
要有她名字的信用卡
She want a credit card with her name on it.
而这些都不是免费的 不是吗
Ain't no such thing as free, right?
天下就没有免费的女人
When it come to pussy, there ain't no free.
我该走了
I gotta go.
一直在弄这个
Been working on this one.
明天就能搞定另外两部公用电话线路
You'll get the lines on the other two payphones tomorrow.
这么说都接上了?
So we up?
- 低层公寓区的公用电话都接上了 - 我们听听
- On the low-rise payphones, yeah. - Let's hear it.
明白吗 我是说他根本不愿付工资
See, what I'm talking about is he ain't paid no one,
他还以为这样做得对
Hejust think it's right to do it.
知道会怎样吗 我可不会这么算了
See how it goes? So I ain't got shit.
我不会这么算了
I ain't got it.
该死 说真的?
Damn, for real?
你想想他这样还不是因为家里有人撑腰
Thinking he all that because he got his family back.
- 嘿 正来劲呢 - 这是非监控电话
- Hey, it was getting good. - It's unmonitored.
- 是什么 - 非监控
- It's what? - Unmonitored.
我们不能监听 非监控电话上的对话
We can't listen to a conversation on an unmonitored payphone.
什么意思
What's that mean?
我们已经在庭院的 公用电话上装了窃听器
We got a tap on the courtyard payphone.
到明天 我们还能接上 高层公寓区的两部公用电话
By tomorrow, we'll be up on two near the high-rises.
但除非我们确认是目标在使用电话
But we can't listen to anything
否则我们不能窃听对话内容
Unless we know one of our targets is using the phone.
所以我们得长时间守在楼顶上...
So we gotta be out there on those rooftops for hours...
看着那些混蛋聊电话?
Watching these assholes talk on the phone?
没错
Yep.
这太扯了
It's more bullshit.
探员
Detective,
在我们小组 这就是工作
This right here, this is the job.
你调来市区刑侦科
Now, when you came downtown to CID,
还指望做什么工作?
What kind of work were you expecting?
那么你打算怎么做
So what are you gonna do?
我一周内回不来 这案子才刚开始
I can't get back here in a week, this case is taking off.
你跟Rawls这样说?
You tell Rawls that?
- 不 - McNulty 3号线
- No. - McNulty, Line 3.
喂
Yeah?
在哪
Where at?
800号街后巷 好的 我记下了
800 block, in the rear. Yeah, I got it.
谢谢 好的
Thanks. Yeah.
我们还在等鉴证小组 知道他们什么时候能到吗？
We're still waiting on a lab unit. Do you have an ETA?
不知道 他们都出任务了
Negative. They're all out.
那死狗把Norris也吓着了
Damn dog got Norris, too.
你就没想过提前跟我说一声?
You didn't think to warn me?
那多没意思
Too much fun not to.
该死
Damn.
他是你们的嫌疑人吗
Yeah. Is he one of yours?
发现他的时候他穿着凯芙拉防弹衣
We found him with Kevlar,
跟上周Worden接手的案子一样
like the one Worden caught last week.
我们认为可能有联系
We thought it might be a connection.
- 是的 有联系 - 怎么说
- Yeah, it connects. - How so?
无名氏 但是抢劫团伙的成员
Don't have a name, but he's part of a stick-up crew.
上月洗劫了一个藏毒点
Took off a stash house last month.
我们的目标Barksdale正在报复他们
My guy, Barksdale, is coming back on them.
大张旗鼓的报复
In a big way.
他们这些折磨足够把他 杀死个四 五次了
Jesus, they must've killed him four or five times.
砍得浑身是伤 用烟头烫他
Cut him in a dozen places, burned him with cigarettes.
这是个酷刑派对
Torture-fest is what it was.
这儿不像是犯罪现场
Doesn't look like your scene, either.
姿势暗合了前集中Avon说的白人打猎的故事
在另一个地方折磨他 然后把他扔到这儿示众
Fuck him up somewhere else, dump him here for all to see.
- 有什么有用的线索? - 还没有
- Anything we can use? - Not yet.
我们正在窃听几部电话 听到有用的我会通知你们
We're up on some phones. If I hear anything, I'll let you know.
- 接22线 - 22线
- Bring 22. - 22.
有人过来了吗 还是我们就这么 等着尸体在我们面前腐烂?
Anything yet? Or are we just gonna let this guy go ripe on us?
你们在等鉴证小组?
You been waiting for crime lab?
等了一个多小时了
Over an hour.
只有两个小组出任务
Only two units on the street.
都跑到市议会主席家了
Both are up at the City Council President's house.
那儿出了什么事
What happened there?
有人偷了他的草坪家具
Someone stole his lawn furniture.
他们在给空空如也的庭院拍照存证
They're taking pictures of an empty patio,
在后院门上收集指纹
Dusting the backyard gate for latents.
没开玩笑
I kid you not.
我发誓 你要能找出个狗娘养的 把这个警局整顿好...
I swear, you show me the son of a bitch who can fix this police department...
我愿上交一半的加班费
I'd give back half my overtime.
他都被切碎了
He was all cut up and shit.
内脏挂在外边
His insides was hanging out.
被整惨了 我是说 该死
Fucked up, yo. I mean, damn.
有时你得杀鸡儆猴
Sometimes you gotta send a message, yo.
我是说 当你拿起电话时
I mean, when you picked up that phone,
你怎么知道他们会怎么做?
What did you think they were gonna do?
这些个鸟事都是游戏的一部分 你知道的
All that shit is in the game. You know that.
是啊  就像你和那女孩 嗯?
Yeah. Like you and that girl, huh?
哪个女孩
What girl?
公寓里那个
The one in the apartment.
你跟我们说起过 记得吗
The one you told us about, remember?
我是说 我喜欢你对杀人的看法 你知道吗
I mean, I like what you said about all that killing, you know?
尤其是你说的杀人没有必要
Especially that part about how it ain't gotta be like that.
只要卖货和走人
Just sell the shit and move on.
给我买杯姜汁啤酒 剩下的给你自己买点东西
Get me a ginger ale and get something for yourself.
我记得 但这事不一样 不是吗
Yeah, I remember that. But it ain't like that, is it?
是 我知道 我知道不一样
Yeah, I know. I know it ain't.
重点是他的眼睛 他的眼睛被挖出来了
Thing about it was his eye. His eye was blown out.
而另一只还睁着
And the other one was open.
嘿 Dee 这事让我心乱如麻
And yo, Dee, it fucks me up.
就像他在看着 看着这一切 懂吗
It's like he's looking out, like he sees everything, you know?
别想它了
Don't think about it.
我不...
I can't…
操
Fuck!
嘿
Yo.
忘了这破事儿吧
Let that shit go.
忘了吧
Just let it go.
Barksdale的小鬼在打电话
Barksdale kid on the line.
他在呼某人
He's beeping someone.
- 嘿 - 什么事
- Yo. - What up?
他回电了
Yo, you ain't him.
别挂
Hold on.
嘿 Strings 我是Dee
Yo, Strings! This is Dee.
- 喂 - 喂 你呼我?
- Yeah. - Yeah, you hit me?
对
Yeah,
我想知道你是否认识 一个年轻的小毒贩
I wanted to know if you know a young hopper,
被警察抓走那个
The one they got down there.
哪个
Which one?
那个蠢材 他给了警察一拳
The fool, drop in there with a punch.
认识 他怎么了
Yeah, what about him?
他有麻烦了 对吧?
He got some problems, right?
你指的什么?
What you mean?
是时候让他回家了 不是吗
Enough to bring home, right?
你知道 哥们 随便吧
You know, man, whatever.
好
All right.
Bodie快回家了
They're bringing Bodie home.
一个浅肤色的小鬼
A young boy who was with him,
在墓园就跟他在一起
Light-skinned kid from the cemetery.
哪儿
Where?
Argyle街800号后面小巷
In the alley behind 800 block of Argyle,
低层公寓区对面
Across from the low-rises.
枪杀?
Shot?
- 被捅 被打 被烧 - 天啊
- Stabbed, beaten, burned. - Jesus.
- 对啊 我们得告诉Omar - 是的
- Yeah, we gotta get with Omar. - Yeah.
不错
Impressive.
很少见被告会对青少年犯罪听证会
I don't often see a respondent come so prepared
做如此充分的准备
For a juvenile commitment meeting.
除了Preston的保荐人签署的声明
In addition to the signed statements from Preston's sponsors...
警察竞技联盟：通过体育运动 建立社区未成年人和警察的良好关系 培养守法意识
对方来自警察竞技联盟
At the Police Athletic League...
我还有一张已兑现的支票复本...
I also have a Photostatted copy of a cashed check...
能证明他已经在 Baltimore市社区大学...
Which indicates that he is enrolled in the GED program...
注册了普通教育水平课程
At the Baltimore City Community College.
我能否问一下 为什么这位 年轻人能请得起不止一位...
Can I ask how this young man is able to afford not one...
而是两位贵事务所的律师呢 Levy先生?
But two attorneys from your firm, Mr. Levy?
法官阁下 这是免费专业服务
This is pro bono, Your Honor.
我们事务所致力于优先帮助一些
My firm is making it a priority to identify a number of city youths
危机中的城市青年
Who are in crisis,
并努力帮他们恢复正常生活
And to undertake efforts to reorder their lives.
请原谅 我不得不注意到你的当事人
Excuse me, I can't help but notice that your client
正面临贩卖毒品的犯罪指控
Is under a delinquent petition for the sale of narcotics,
和袭警的少年犯罪指控
And further, for assault on a police officer.
除此之外 他还擅自离开少管所
Beyond that, he walked away from a JSA facility.
法官阁下 我的当事人愿意承认
You Honor, my client stands ready to acknowledge
他有段时间参与了少量的毒品销售...
That he was involved for a time in the sale of a small amount of drugs...
交易中他没有获取报酬...
A transaction for which he received no remuneration...
而是被社区中
Having been manipulated
年长毒贩所操纵
By older traffickers in his neighborhood.
那是一个错误 法官阁下
That was a mistake, Your Honor.
已记录
So noted.
不论如何  我们主张Preston
How ever, we will contend that it was Preston
是警察暴力的受害者...
Who was the victim of a brutal police beating...
而证据还在他身上 法官阁下
Indications of which are still evident on him, Your Honor.
他只是还击
He struck back,
下手重了点但纯属自卫 法官阁下
Wildly and in self-defense, Your Honor.
擅自离开少管所的指控呢
And the walk-away?
Preston离开Cheltenham少管所时 仍处在强烈的药物作用下
Preston was heavily medicated when he left the Cheltenham facility.
在当时情况下 法官阁下...
In that state, Your Honor...
他只是单纯地想回去看望他祖母
He was simply trying to get back to see his grandmother.
当你离开少管所时
Did you know what you were doing
你知道自己在干什么吗 孩子?
When you left the Boys' Village, son?
不 我当时脑子一团糟
No, I was messed up.
还有什么要补充吗
Anything else you'd like to add?
就...
Just...
我不知道...
I don't know...
我准备重新做人
I'm ready to be good.
对于上述指控的聆讯 会在六个月内进行...
Pending a hearing on these charges to be scheduled within six months...
被告可以待在家中 由其祖母监管
I'm putting the respondent on home monitoring with his grandmother.
法官阁下
Your honor,
恐怕Brodus夫人没有电话...
I'm afraid Mrs. Brodus doesn't have a telephone...
来接听监管电话
For any monitoring calls.
她只有少量固定收入 法官阁下
She's on a fixed income, Your Honor.
那么他能否一周两次 给他的监督官打电话
How about he calls his probation officer twice a week?
行 都可以...
Cool. Whatever...
法官阁下
Your Honor.
McNulty的名片 留言:911("紧急")
嘿 Bubbles 搞什么把戏呢?
Yo, Bubbles, what's the game?
嘿 Johnny
Hey, Johnny.
- 焕然一新嘛 啊? - 是啊
- Rubbing them down, huh? - Yeah.
- Uck - Bubs
这儿耍什么把戏呢?
What is the scam out here?
货真价实
Ain't no scam.
谢谢 女士
Thank you, ma'am.
如你所见 正当工作 合法收入
What you got here is an honest day's work for an honest day's pay.
对吧 Lavelle
Right, Lavelle?
正式工先生啊 Bubbles
Mr. Straight Time, Bubbles.
别人有所期盼 总得给点回馈吧
Gotta give something back when they least expect it.
我和Uck也要有所行动
Me and Uck, here, we got something on, too.
我们有个计划
We got a plan.
- 不是吧 - 说真的
- No shit. - For real.
嘿 我们准备打劫铜料工坊
Yo, we're gonna take off on the copper house.
该死 你刚出来两天就玩这么大
Damn, your first two days out and you get dramatic on me.
- 铜料工坊 - 一定能拿下 伙计
- Copper house. - Got to be got, homes.
- 怎么对付栅栏 - 去他的栅栏
- What about the fence? - Fuck the fence.
- 狗怎么办 - 去他的狗
- What about the dog? - Fuck the dog.
我无所事事的时候 就一直在想
All that time I was resting, it got me thinking.
我觉得已经万无一失了
It got good to me, too.
铜料工坊 天呐!
Copper house. Gracious.
我得走了 能付我工钱吗
I gotta go, can you cash me out?
Bubs 如果你没有梦想 你他妈还能有什么
If you ain't got dreams, Bubs, what the fuck you got?
谢啦 快点吧 梦想家
Thank you. Come on, dreamer.
喂
Yeah.
目标之一在用电话
One of ours on the line.
已窃听
Got him.
Carv还在吗
Is Carv still there?
等会儿
Hold a second.
Carv 你的电话
Carv, call for you!
来了 喂
Yeah, hello?
你绝对无法相信我看见谁了
You ain't gonna believe who I'm looking at right now.
他又逃出来了?
Again he walks off?
叮 第三回合
Ding! Round three.
- 嘿 - 怎么了 伙计
- Yo. - What up, man?
嘿 Stink 出什么事
Yo, Stink, what up?
忘了规矩了 蠢货?
Where are your manners, fool?
哦 我的错
Oh, my bad, yeah.
你他妈的得保持头脑清醒 小子
You need to keep your fucking head, boy.
我忘了
Forgot.
你还好吗 你在哪
What's up? Where you at?
你在哪
Where you at?
我在Pit区这边 刚回家...
I'm down in the Pit. I just came home...
附近没人 我就想知道出了什么事
I don't see nobody around, ljust wanted to know what was up.
一切正常 伙计
Ain't nothing going late, man.
明天来找我们 哥们
Just catch us tomorrow, man.
- 行吗 - 行 可以
- All right? - All right, yeah.
好的 回见
All right. Later.
"无关"?
"Non-pertinent"?
你怎么能记成无关的
How do you log that non-pertinent?
没提到毒品
No drug talk.
他们用密码来隐藏 呼机和电话号码
They use codes that hide their pager and phone numbers.
然后当他们打电话的时候
And when someone does use a phone,
也不称呼名字
They don't use names.
如果有人用了名字 别人也会提醒他别用
And if someone does use a name, he's reminded not to.
这些都是有用的证据
All of that is valuable evidence.
什么的证据
Of what?
阴谋
Conspiracy.
阴谋?
Conspiracy?
我们在构建些东西 探员
We're building something here, detective.
我们从零开始构建
We're building it from scratch.
所有细节决定成败
All the pieces matter.
懂吗
All right?
相关
见鬼
Shit.
操
Shit!
你他妈是来真的?
Are you fucking serious?
操 哥们
Fuck, man.
你从少管所逃一次 我们就扁你一次
You keep walking away from JSA, we keep kicking your ass.
你要那样我们奉陪
I'm all right with that if you are.
我不是逃出来的 哥们
I ain't walk away from nowhere, man.
看我后边口袋
Check my back pocket.
"家庭监管"?
"Home monitoring"?
是啊 伙计
Yeah, man.
对黑鬼动粗前如果你能先问问
If you ask questions before you start wilding on niggers,
就能省很多麻烦
You might save some trouble.
你他妈怎么回得了家的?
How the fuck are you home?
脑袋不太灵光啊 伙计
You ain't bright, man.
青少年法庭法官给的
Juvenile judge, man.
他看出我有潜力 希望我能有大成就
He saw my potential. He expects big things from me.
是吗 比如什么
Yeah, like what?
不知道 大学 法学院 医学院 诸如此类的好事
I don't know, college, law school, medical school, all that good shit.
说真的 你怎么出来的
Seriously, how are you out?
听着 我来告诉你们点事
Look, I'm gonna tell you something.
好吧 只是个人观点 但...
Okay, this is just my opinion, but...
市里的青少年培养体系糟透了
The juvenile system in this city is fucked up.
就他妈是个大笑话 无意冒犯
It's a big-ass fucking joke. No offense.
见鬼
Fucking fuck!
不如载我回祖母家 那我们就扯平了
You could give me a ride down to my grandma's, we'll call it even.
坐后面 混蛋
In back, fucknuts.
Jay
从马路上滚开
Get outta the street!
贱人
Bitch!
- 嘿 - 嘿
- Hey. - Hey.
怎么了 你想干什么
What's up? What you need?
这个月的月钱晚到了 你不觉得吗
Little late in the month for this shit, isn't it?
什么意思
What you mean?
给我阿姨的 她中了四合彩
For my aunt, she hit the Match Four.
你偷我东西 Cass?
You stealing from me, Cass?
干嘛
What?
Raymond 你今天很精神
Raymond, You look fresh today.
因为昨晚"开荤"了
Got laid last night, that's why.
哦 是吗 那你屁眼还痛吗(故意说成他被操了)
Oh, yeah? Your asshole still hurting?
打给Jimmy
Call Jimmy.
怎么了 老板
What's up, boss?
Rawls终于读了
Rawls finally got around to reading
之前McNulty想给他看的报告
The office reports that McNulty tried to give him.
他想要Diedre Kresson案和另两起...
He wants arrest warrants for Diedre Kresson...
弹道匹配的公宅谋杀案的逮捕令
And the two project murders that match up to that gun.
我了解
I know.
拜托 Jay 别搞错了
Come on, Jay, be right on this.
没办法 Rawls说了算 他今天就要逮捕令
I can't. It's Rawls, he wants warrants today.
好 没问题
All right, no problem.
所以我们他妈的该抓谁
So who the fuck are we supposed to charge?
你有个指证D'Angelo Barksdale...
You got a witness that puts D'Angelo Barksdale...
案发当晚在犯罪现场的目击者
At the scene of the murder, the night of the murder.
弹道学检测表明Kresson案与...
You got a ballistics match between the Kresson girl
Barksdale地盘的公宅 谋杀案使用的枪械一致
And the two dead mopes in the project where Barksdale hangs.
从这下手
Run with it.
证据不足啊 大陪审团不会同意的
This weak-ass shit is not gonna get past the Grand Jury.
先起诉 然后再搜证
Charge the mope, and work it more afterward.
打给Jimmy 告诉他
Call Jimmy, let him know.
嘿
Yo.
好 听好了 新安排
All right, listen up. New deal.
Wallace 现在开始你跟Latroy 还有Peaches负责藏货
Wallace, you're gonna be on the stash now with Latroy and Peaches.
Sterling呢
What about Sterling?
他在Crescent街负责望风
He's gonna be down on Crescent, looking out for a while.
- Cassandra也是 - 出什么事了?
- Cassandra, too. - What happened?
没事
Nothing.
那为什么要变动
Why you wanna change up, then?
黑鬼 我什么事都得向你解释吗
Nigger, I gotta explain shit to you now?
是Stringer Bell的呼机号?
Stringer Bell's pager number?
还有Stinkum的 我很肯定
Stinkum's too, I'm pretty sure.
很好
Very sweet.
如果他们到处晃 那大家都省了麻烦
If they moved around, then nobody would have problems.
他们有点懒 你知道...
They're a little lazy, you know...
他们对庭院里那个 公用电话使用过于频繁了
Tend to go to that one payphone in the courtyard a little too much.
天啊
Jesus.
他早上9:00就喝醉了?
He's lit at 9:00 in the morning?
或者从昨晚醉到现在
Or from the night before.
探员
Detective.
Polk探员
Detective Polk.
对 我是McNulty Bunk呼我
Yeah, it's McNulty. Bunk paged me.
好的
All right.
你今天还来干嘛
Why did you even come in today?
我有些....
I had some....
假装你人在这?
To pretend that you were here?
来填出勤单?
To fill out a run sheet?
中尉 我知道我上周 缺勤了几天 但...
I know I missed a couple of days last week, Lieutenant, but--
你上两周的出勤单上可是全勤
I got a run sheet from you every day for the last two weeks.
其中两次是Carv的笔迹
Twice in Carv's handwriting,
两次是Prez 一次是McNulty吧 我猜
Twice it was Prez, once it was McNulty.
他们都替你打掩护
They covered for you.
但我不会
But I won't.
好吧 中尉 我...
Well, Lieutenant, l....
我不知道 我不是很热衷 这些毒品案 你知道吗
I don't know. I'm not really up for this drug thing, you know?
如果Mahone在这 也许我可以...
Maybe if Mahone was here, I could...
更投入 多学点新花样
Get into it more, learn some new tricks.
靠 为什么你不把我踢回 财产犯罪科 这样大家都高兴
Hell, why don't you just send me back to Property and keep everyone happy?
更正:财产犯罪 侦办包括偷盗 纵火 损坏公物等
送你回财产犯罪科 好让你再多玩两周?
Send you back to Property Crimes so you can binge for two more weeks?
我不会那么做
I'm not doing that.
- 中尉 求你... - 你被踢给我 Augie
- Lieutenant, please-- - You were dumped on me, Augie.
但到此为止 我不踢人
But it ends there. I don't dump people.
你今天要么到楼顶上
You either go out on those rooftops today
跟其他人一起监视公用电话...
To watch payphones with the others...
要么去医务室报个到
Or you go over to the medical office and check yourself in.
医务室?
Medical?
酗酒治疗
For alcohol abuse.
要么戒酒 要么上楼顶喝去
Either dry yourself out or go up on those rooftops wet.
给你几分钟考虑
Take a few minutes and think on it.
他们去哪儿了
Where'd they go?
谁
Who?
中尉...
Lieutenant...
我们需要一两个文件柜
We need a file cabinet or two.
这些文件 我是说...
The paperwork from this, I mean...
太多了
There's a lot of it.
中尉...
Lieutenant...
长官...
Sir...
我要去....
I'm going to....
希望顺利结案
Good luck with the case.
他妈的Rawls 他就想 把案子搞砸了好整我
Fucking Rawls, he's fucking up the case to get to me.
不 他这么做只为 处理掉前面三个案子
No, he's fucking it up for three paper clearances on prior cases.
不是针对你
It ain't personal.
他只靠D'Angelo在案发现场的传闻...
All he's got is D'Angelo at the scene through hearsay...
还有发现弹道结果 和两件无关的毒品凶杀案匹配
And a ballistics match to a couple unrelated drug murders.
怎么控告啊
How can he charge that?
为了破案率 他想怎么控告都行
He can charge anything he wants to get credit for clearance.
大陪审团不起诉 他就结案 维持破案率就行
Grand Jury doesn't indict, he drops the case, keeps his stats.
我要去告诉他 他妈的该怎么做
I'll go tell him what the fuck he can do.
- 不 不行 - 我这正要有点眉目
- No you don't. - I'm trying to build something here.
Rawls就把手指插进我眼睛里了
Rawls just sticks a finger in my eye.
- 你跟Landsman谈过吗 - Jay罩不住了
- You talk to Landsman? - Jay can't fix this.
Rawls让他明早前准备好逮捕令
Rawls told him to have the warrants typed and ready by morning.
就为破案率好看 他要去 控告一个他证明不了的凶手?
He's gonna charge murders he can't prove just to get the stats?
还把我们手头的案子给搞砸
And fuck up our case in the process.
一旦起诉文件中泄露Kresson案 的动机和弹道信息...
We give up ballistics info and motive for the Kresson killing...
Avon Barksdale就会改变行动模式
In the charging documents, and Avon Barksdale is gonna change up.
变不了的 他就会销毁
And what he don't change up he'll clean up.
- 总得有人告诉Rawls - Rawls才不在乎呢
- Someone should tell Rawls. - Rawls couldn't care less.
他想赶我回家 要破案率 他只在乎这些
He wants me home, and the stats, that's all.
- 那我们跟Daniels说 - Daniels?
- Then we take it to Daniels. - Daniels?
- 这是他的案子 他会争取的 - 他才不会
- It's his case, he'll fight for it. - He won't do shit.
他很倔 但是他是个好人
He plays stiff every now and then, but he's a good man.
你开玩笑吧
Are you kidding me?
几周来他一直想阻止我们的行动
He's been trying to put the brakes on this for weeks now.
这会给他一个停止行动的借口
This'll be his new excuse to close shop.
听着 总之你们得尽快行动了 很遗憾
Look, you guys gotta make your move soon, I'm sorry to say.
- Freamon - 行了 Bunk 保重
- Freamon. - All right, Bunk, take care.
我们跟Daniels说
We tell Daniels.
操Daniels这马屁精 和他往上爬的野心
Fuck Daniels and his ass-kissing up-the-chain-of-command ambition.
还有别的选择吗
What other choice you got, huh?
找Daniels 如果他争取 最好
We go to Daniels. If he fights, he fights.
如果他向Rawls妥协 那管他娘的
If he gives it up to Rawls, then fuck it,
反正案子是查不下去了
We were never gonna do the case anyway.
行 就这样吧
All right, come on.
它妈的白痴!
Fucking idiot!
- 拜托 起来 蠢货 - 我受伤了 伙计
- Come on, get up, stupid. - I'm hurt, man.
你在干什么 别碰我
What are you doing? Leave me alone!
怎么 你嗑药了还是怎样
What, are you on dope or something?
- 差不多吧 - 快 起来
- Mostly, yes. - Come on, get up.
噢 你想把我肠子扯出来啊
Oh, You trying to rip out my guts?
- 见鬼 - 怎么 难道你还想杀我
- Fuck. - What, are you trying to kill me, man?
- 等一下 你想去哪儿 - 听着 我去找人帮忙
- Wait! Where are you going? - Listen, I gotta get help.
别把我一个人扔在这 你得跟我待在这儿
You can't leave me here. You gotta stay with me.
- 行 我们先移到路边 - 别走
- all right. Let's go over to the curb. - stay with me.
快去找人帮忙 伙计 待在着做什么
Just go get help, man! What are you doing?
- 待着别动 - 行啦
- Stay there! - all right.
臭小子 你身上溅出来的是什么
Damn, boy! What the hell come out of you?
Campbell的洋葱汤
Onion soup, Campbell's.
- 耶 我的计划 - 跑 阿甘 快跑(阿甘正传台词)
- Yeah, my plan! - Run, Forrest, run!
你们该去找Foerster或者行政副局长
You could go to Foerster, or the Deputy Ops.
找我哭诉干嘛
Why come crying to me?
怎么不去找你的法官朋友
Why not go to your friend, the judge?
我不认为一个巡回法庭的法官...
I don't see a circuit court judge being able to argue...
能劝服市凶杀科主管放弃 对三桩凶杀案凶手的起诉...
The city homicide commander out of three murders...
即使这些案子都证据不足
Even if the cases are all weak sisters.
现在是抉择时刻 要么争取 要么闭嘴 中尉
It's put-up or shut-up time, Lieutenant.
要么你站出来 要么我们滚蛋
Either you step up or you send us all home.
所以都取决于我?
So this is on me?
我不认为还有其他负责人
I don't see anyone else in charge of this detail.
Rawls是警长
Rawls is a major.
Rawls是个混蛋
Rawls is an asshole.
我指的是 他警衔比我高
My point is, he ranks me on this.
McNulty 你大概完全不在乎上下级
Chain of command might mean nothing to you, McNulty.
我跟你说什么来着?
What'd I tell you?
嘿 最近怎样
Yo, how we doing?
还不赖
We doing good.
你知道 如果你说还不赖....
You know, if you say we doing good....
怎么?
What's up?
所以那些打劫家伙的下场 已经众所皆知了吧 对吗?
So the word is out about these stick-up boys, right?
是啊 都听说了
Yeah, y'all being heard.
好吧
All right.
就是那边的小子
There goes shorty right there.
怎么了 伙计 你知道...
What's up, man, you know...
我说话算话
I'm a man of my word.
我说过4,000块给Omar...
I said it would be $4,000 to Omar...
每个小的拿2,000 所谓团队协作嘛
$2,000 on each of the young ones, this being a team effort.
那个报信的小鬼拿500...
I'm putting $500 in the boy's hand who's doing the scope...
你传递消息 也拿500...
$500 in your hand for doing the relay...
Wee-Bey和Bird动的手 也拿500
Put $500 in Wee-Bey and Bird's hands for doing the muscling up.
- 好的 - 另一件事办得怎样了
- All right. - How you doing with that other thing?
什么
What?
大家都有点消沉 是吧
Everybody a little depressed, right?
噢 是啊 你知道 并不意外
Oh, yeah, you know, ain't no surprises yet.
周五大家都没钱 没事可做...
Cut everybody loose on Friday...
不过是一群四处求人的贱货
And they all just a bunch of begging-ass bitches.
我是说 还没发现谁还有钱呢
I mean, ain't nobody showed no money since.
- 继续好好干 伙计 - 好 你知道的
- You gonna keep it humming, cuz? - Yeah, you know.
哦 你还想还手
Oh! You got your hands up.
你就照这么干下去
You keep on doing like how you're doing
我们会考虑增加你的提成
We'll talk about points on the package.
- 行吗 - 行
- All right? - All right.
好好干
Keep it humming.
当然 绝对的
Yeah, most def.
好 那再见
All right, then.
- 没多少 你拿着 - 好
- Take it light, but take it. - yeah.
- 40美分 - 不是40一尺 不是
- 40 cents. - Not 40 cents a foot, no sir.
对 不是 出于尊重 我得说...
No sir. Look, respectfully, I gotta tell you...
如果是40美分一尺 您直接去家得宝买
For 40 cents a foot, you might as well go to Home Depot,
就好了
Pay them.
他们会叫价45或50美分一尺
They're gonna charge you 45 or 50 cents a foot.
起码不是偷来的铜
For copper that isn't stolen.
听着 好吧 35美分一尺
Look, all right, 35 cents a foot.
这可是出于对您的尊重
And that's in respect I have for y'all,
还有您建那些高质量的房子...
What you're doing in our community...
对社区做出的贡献
With these quality domiciles here.
30美分一尺 卖不卖随你
Thirty cents a foot, take it or leave it.
我明白您想早日结案的心情 我理解
I understand the interest in clearing these cases, I do.
但是现在起诉这些谋杀案...
But charging those murders now...
并把我们掌握的信息 放进起诉文件里...
And putting the information that we have into the charging documents....
这案子很明了 中尉
I just call them like I see them, Lieutenant.
三宗谋杀案 同一把枪
Three murders, same gun,
有人目击到Barksdale那小子 在其中一个犯罪现场
We got this Barksdale kid right at the scene on the one.
我们正在窃听
We're up on the wire.
刚开始收集到一些有用的消息
We're starting to pull good information.
你贸然起诉 Barksdale就会 针对我们的行动做出调整
You charge these prematurely and Barksdale will change up on us.
- 我们已经做的工作就... - 你看...
- The work we've already done-- - Look...
我没办法告诉你怎么查你的案子 我只负责我的案子
I can't tell you how to run your case, I can only run my own.
警长...
Major...
我是在求你帮忙
I'm asking as a favor.
帮忙
As a favor.
是的 长官 帮忙
Yes, sir. A favor.
这样的话...
In that case...
不
No.
不好意思
Sorry.
你今天下班很早
You got home from work early today.
对 工作没劲透了
Yep. Work sucks.
今天能跟我们一起吃饭吗
Are we eating dinner with you?
干嘛不呢
Why not?
答应我们吃烤宽面条
You promised we'd eat lasagna.
那我们就去吃意大利菜吧
So we'll go to Little ltaly.
去Sab餐厅点烤宽面条
Get some lasagna at Sab's.
- 你从不做饭 - 对 做饭也很没劲
- You never cook. - Yeah, cooking sucks, too.
你哪位
Who's this?
嘿 我要见你
Hey, yo, I wanna see him.
是谁
Who?
为了Brandon 我的小弟
Brandon, my boy.
铜料工坊 哼
Copper house, yo.
有料
Was the shit.
我计划的 Bubs
My plan, Bubs.
Johnny有个计划
Johnny had a plan.
闪一边去 混球
Get out the way, motherfuckers.
今天是白人小子节
This here is White Boy Day.
- 我也有个计划 - 什么
- I got a plan, too. - What?
我们等那个占便宜
We're gonna wait for that cheap-ass,
投机的老混蛋...
Speculating motherfucker...
把那些上好的铜条
To put that good copper line
放到他修的排屋里
Back into them row houses he's fixing up.
然后 在墙没砌好前...
Then, before the drywall get up...
我们溜进去 再把铜条偷回来
We creep back in there, and steal that shit right back.
30美分一尺
30 cents a foot.
就为这个也得报复一下那混球 你说呢
Gotta come back at the motherfucker for that, you know?
对
Yeah.
你还好吧
You good?
还能再来一支
I could top off with one more.
- 对 - 再一支
- Yeah. - Just one more.
Johnny还有钱
Johnny got it.
马上回来
I'll be back.
今晚我陪孩子
It's my night with the kids.
你们什么也找不到 因为我啥也没干
You ain't gonna find nothing, because I didn't do nothing!
别搜我了好不好 伙计?
Why don't you just leave me alone, man?
白人不能在街上走么 为什么抓我
A white man can't walk down the street? What's that about?
拜托 哥们
Come on, man!
搞得乱七八糟的
It's messed up, all right?
偏见!
Profiling!
怎么 因为我是白人 对吧
What? It's 'cause I'm white, right?
干嘛不让我....
Why don't you let me....
噢 哥们 你找到什么了 什么东西
Oh, man, what the fuck's that? What's that?
这小子真不走运
That boy ain't got no luck.
好 等着
All right. Hold up!
- 嘿 - 嘿
- Hey. - Hey.
那么
So,
你准备怎么用那笔钱
What are you going to do with your money?
你知道你该怎么做吗 拿着那笔钱
You know what you should do? Take the whole roll
关心一下你的妞
And do something nice for your girl.
你有个妞 没错吧
You do have a girl, right?
好吧 反正 你有钱能为自己找一个了
Yeah. Anyway, you've got enough money to go get yourself one now.
你为什么要把Sterling给踢开
Why'd you punk Sterling like you did?
我是说 他就因为那事儿中的枪
I mean, he did get shot behind this shit.
我没把他踢开
I didn't punk him.
那为什么安排他去望风
So why are you dropping the lookout?
还有Cass
Cass, too.
因为他们是贼
'Cause they was thieving.
他俩都是
Both of them.
我没给他们钱 他们很不爽
They got pissed 'cause I wasn't paying them.
所以Sterling开始小瓶地偷
So Sterling started shaking up the vials,
交给Cass
Handing off to Cass.
她再到其他地方转手
She was selling on the side.
你没跟别人说? Stinkum...Bodie?
You didn't tell anybody? Stinkum, Bodie?
他们不知道?
They don't know?
如果我告诉他们 你猜他们会怎样
If I tell them, what you think they're going to do?
大概会用球棒修理Sterling吧 还有Cassandra
They're going to take a baseball bat to Sterling. Cassandra, too.
会闹大 对吧?
It's too much drama, right?
所以我就安排他俩离货远点
So, I just took them both off the stash.
那你干嘛不付钱给我们呢
So why didn't you pay us?
那样不对
That wasn't right.
听着 哥们...
Listen, man...
Stringer认为我们中有告密者
Stringer thought we had a snitch down here.
Jump-out 指在房车内监视 待命行动的警察
你知道的 那些蹲点的条子
You know, with the jump-out,
Omar 那些一干烂事
Omar, all that shit.
所以他让我疏远你们一阵子
So he told me to punk you all for a little while.
看看谁到周末还有钱
See who was still holding money at the end of the week.
他们告的密吗
Was they snitching?
Sterling和Cass?
Sterling and Cass?
不 他们只是偷货
No, man, just thieving.
Orioles在第一局2-0领先
2-0, Orioles,in the first inning.
行 去凶杀科
All right, going to Homicide.
好了 你们两个到那边去坐着 行吗
Okay, you two, you sit right here, okay?
别到处乱走
Don't wander off.
- 爸? - 什么事
- Dad? - What?
明天上课 妈妈让我们...
It's a school night. Mom said we had to--
我知道 我知道 很快 你们就待在这儿
I know, I know. We will. Just stay there.
第一局 二 三垒有人 无人出局
Runners at second and third, nobody out yet here in the first inning.
轮到Mora击球 球投太高了
Here's Mora at the plate, and the pitch is high.
Lopez投球 球出界了
Lopez on the mound. The pitch is outside.
15投10好球
15 pitches and 10 of them have been balls.
一个右外野滚地球
It's a ground ball down the right-field line.
C64呼叫K总台
64-Charlie to Central K.
你准备好了?
You up to this?
复仇 Omar 复仇
Pay it back, Omar. Pay it back.
为什么我们不去警察局
Why we ain't in a real police office?
我们跟你差不多 Omar
We're a little like you, Omar.
这里是我们的天下 为自己卖命
Out here on our own, playing the game for ourselves.
有时候很辛苦的
Hard way to go sometimes.
对你的朋友 我很遗憾
Sorry about your friend.
Avon是个无耻混蛋
Avon is one sick bastard.
当然 他自有理由
Of course, he had his reasons.
首先 你们确实抢了他的货
For one thing, you all did take his stash.
其次 他是要找你 Omar
For another, he's looking for you, Omar.
所以他才要用烟头烫
That's what all the cigarette burns were about.
弄断手指 折断手臂
The broken fingers and cracked forearms.
他希望你的小弟把你供出来
He wanted your boy to give you up.
地址 街区
An address, a street.
那小子很有骨气
Kid had heart.
对
Yeah.
我知道你现在很想回家...
I know you want to go to wherever it is you lay your head...
拿起你心爱的猎枪
And pick up that sawed-off you like so much,
出去找他们报仇
And go on the hunt.
这是你这类人想做的事
That's how a man like you wants to carry.
这么做也没错
You wouldn't be wrong.
是 没错
No, you wouldn't.
但是Omar 一个人拿把双筒枪 可报不了仇
But one man with two barrels ain't enough, Omar.
你可以做你想做的事
Now, you're going to do what you're going to do.
但你要是能向我们提供Barksdale 和他的手下的情报...
But whatever else you can give us on Barksdale and his people...
也能打击他们
That can go to hurting him, too.
只要把你知道的说出来
Just throw us what you can.
我来告诉你一件事怎么样
Let me tell you all something, all right?
一人做事一人当 就这么简单
What I do, I do, straight like that.
你们犯不着自找麻烦...
Ain't no sense in you all troubling yourselves over that...
因为那是我认为 正确的方式 但现在....
'cause the way I feel right now, today....
你们想从我这知道什么
What do you all need from me?
你最后一次见到Brandon是什么时候
When did you last see Brandon?
周二7点左右 大概更晚一点
Tuesday around 7:00. Maybe later.
他正前往Mindamin...
He was on his way down to Mindamin...
然后是Greek小吃店
And the Greek's after that.
大家都说他在那儿被抓
Everybody's talking about he got snatched up from there.
Baltimore街的Greek小吃店?
The Greek's on Baltimore Street?
对 他爱死了那儿的弹珠游戏
Yeah, he liked to play the pinball games to death.
一个人去的?
He go alone?
对 我也不想那样
Yeah, and I didn't like it none, neither.
但在一个年轻人长大之前
But you can only treat a young man like a boy
只能尽可能把他当小孩子对待
For so long before they buck, you know what I mean?
Bailey被杀后 你一定认为
When Bailey got killed you must have figured
Barksdale正在四处找你寻仇 对吧
Barksdale was coming back on you, right?
Bailey? 拜托
Bailey? Please.
那个黑鬼的仇人还有仇人
That nigger's enemies got enemies.
我还以为他只是找了个错误的地儿下手 被人弄死了
I just figured he tried his hand on the wrong corner and got dropped.
但你担心Brandon的安危 不是吗
But you were worried about Brandon, right?
你看 在我的游戏里...
Look, in my game...
你带几个小鬼 就得保证他们的安全
You take some kid, you play it the safest way you can.
但不意味着躲一辈子
But it ain't about no hiding forever.
听到了吗
You heard?
坦率地说 你要是跟我一样 在这行干这么久...
Frankly, you been in it as long as me...
你就得顾虑自己的名声
You do the thing on your name.
谁找Omar的麻烦 Omar就找谁的麻烦
Anyone going to come after Omar, they know Omar's coming after him.
对 就这么回事
Oh, indeed.
那么 谁找了Brandon的麻烦
So, who came after Brandon?
听说是Wee-Bey...
I heard it might have been Wee-Bey...
还有他小弟Stinkum...
His boy Stinkum...
和Bird
And Bird.
绑人他也有份
He was down with the snatch, too.
那么就这案子你能给我们什么情报?
So, what can you give us on the job?
周二晚7:56 有一个电话...
7:56 Tuesday night, you had an incoming call...
打给D'Angelo Barksdale的 给了他一个公用电话号码
To D'Angelo Barksdale's, giving him the number of a pay phone.
西区的号码 加密了 对吧
Westside exchange. Number's encoded, right?
三分钟后
Three minutes later,
一个低层公寓区的电话 拨打了那个号码
We get another call from the low-rises to that number.
接着 一分半钟后 又是一个低层公寓区的电话...
Then, a half-minute later, you get another call from the low-rises...
呼了Stringer Bell的呼机
To a pager we know is Stringer Bell's.
- 见鬼 - 最后
- I'll be damned. - Finally,
还有一个电话
You get another call.
可能是从一个公用电话打来 大概Stringer Bell回电
Probably from a pay phone. Probably Stringer Bell calling back.
打回底层公寓区庭院
Coming on into the low-rise courts.
四十五分钟后 又一个电话
Forty-five minutes later, another call.
来自同一部公用电话
This one from the same pay phone
打给D'Angelo的呼机 一切就此开始
That went to D'Angelo's pager to start the whole thing off.
发现了吗
You see that?
谋杀发生的时间 就是这时
This is the murder, right here.
这第一个号码
This first number,
他们传给D'Angelo的那个...
The one they sent to D'Angelo...
我想是来自Greek小吃店的一部公用电话
I'm thinking this comes from a pay phone over by the Greek's.
都是你的错
He's on you.
要是周二晚我们就能窃听这些公用电话...
We're up on those pay phones Tuesday night...
我们就能发现这场谋杀案
we catch that murder.
谋杀发生前我们就能知道
We get there before the murder.
这些记录里都有
It's all here on the pen register.
这个打给那个 那个打回来
This one calling that one, that one calling back.
要是我们及时窃听了那些公共电话
We're up on those pay phones when we should be,
他也不会死了
And we have him cold.
但我们还是没做好准备 不是吗
But we're not up in time, are we?
这案子里 我们永远慢人一步
In this case, we're never where we need to be.
都不好过啊?
Bad time for you all?
他反抗了 但你们还是把他逮捕了
He fight, but you arrest.
你看见他被逮捕?
You saw him get arrested?
- 是周二吗 - 周二 对 是周二
- On Tuesday? - Tuesday, yes. Tuesday.
警察吗 是警察把他逮捕的吗
By the police? The police arrested him?
警察 他们用了手铐?
Cops, they handcuffed him?
那这两个家伙呢
What about these guys?
他们跟他一起吗
Were they there with him?
不
No.
没有
No
- 他反抗 你们逮捕了他 - 好的
- He fight, you arrest. - Right.
好了 谢谢 先生 谢谢你
Okay, thank you, sir. Thank you.
对上号了
It's a match.
不行
No.
你得帮我 Rawls警衔比我高
I need help. Rawls ranks me.
中尉 想想你这是在干嘛
Lieutenant, think what you're doing here.
你想绕过Bill Rawls...
You're going to cross Bill Rawls...
这个局里不近人情的混蛋
As ruthless a fuck as we have in this department?
然后去做什么
And to do what?
去争取行政副局长 根本看不上眼的案子
To fight for a case the Deputy of Operations doesn't even want.
不行
No.
我还在乎我的前途 非常感谢
I like my career, thank you very much.
在墓园 你告诉我们
In the cemetery, you were telling us
那个叫Bird的家伙杀了那个工人
That a guy named Bird killed the working man.
对 那个证人
Yeah, the man who testified.
William Gant 对
William Gant. Right.
对 就是Bird做的 我确定
Yeah, Bird did that one, for sure.
- 你怎么知道的 - 大家都知道啊 大姐
- How do you know? - Everybody knows, man.
那个黑鬼走到那人 背后朝他脑袋开枪
Nigger walked up behind the man and shot him in the head.
整个公宅的人都看见了
The whole blessed project saw that much.
Bird为Avon工作?
And Bird worked for Avon?
对 他的杀手之一
Yeah, as one of his shooters.
很喜欢他的那把好枪
Liked to use this real sweet gun he got.
一把点三八 产于奥地利 或澳大利亚或者类似的地方
A .380 from Austria or Australia. Something like that.
我知道他很喜欢那把枪
But I know he loved that gun.
点三八
A .380.
对 点三八 找到他 就能找到那把枪
Yeah, a .380. You get him, you get the gun.
因为Bird蠢到死也不会扔那把枪
'Cause Bird's too dumb to throw a gun like that off.
- 只是一把枪还不够 - 哦 不够?
- A gun alone ain't enough. - Oh, no?
他可以说是Gant被杀后在街上买的
He testifies he bought the gun on the street after Gant was killed.
那要怎么样才够
What would be enough, then?
目击证人
Eyeball witness.
能够为你今天告诉我们的事作证
Some kind of corroboration for what you're telling me here.
- 好 - 好什么
- Okay. - Okay, what?
我来做目击证人
I'm your man.
你目击了谋杀?
You saw the murder?
对
Yeah.
你能指认Bird枪杀了William Gant?
You can ID this man, Bird, as the shooter of William Gant?
你也不怕出庭指证
And you ain't afraid to go into the court downtown
Barksdale团伙的一员?
And testify against one of Barksdale's people?
Omar不知道害怕
Omar don't scare.
事实是 当Daniels中尉
The fact is that while Lt. Daniels
和他的开心乐团忙于...
And his merry band are lost in the swamps...
摆弄着呼机 公用电话和 小型话筒的时候...
Playing with beepers and pay phones and body mikes...
我的人已经找出来Barksdale 和三宗谋杀案的联系
My people have developed information that ties Barksdale to three killings.
D'Angelo Barksdale 而不是Avon
D'Angelo Barksdale, not Avon.
D'Angelo代表Avon
D'Angelo on behalf of Avon.
我们的证人指认
The victim is identified by our witnesses
受害者与Avon Barksdale有关
As being involved with Avon Barksdale.
长官 我们已有进展...
Sir, we're developing--
你们是雷声大雨点小
You're dancing around this thing.
我要起诉三起谋杀案
I'm charging three murders.
你起诉这些案子 我的调查就玩完了
You charge those cases, my investigation folds.
没有一宗案子能过得了庭审 你清楚这点
Not one of those cases is strong enough for court. You know that.
那我们就把Barksdale这小子抓来...
So we bring the Barksdale kid in...
玩点心理战 证据自然就有了
Throw a little mindfuck at him and the case becomes stronger.
已经审过他两次了
You've had him in the box twice before.
第三次他更不会配合
He's gonna go for less the third time.
那我们就重新调查 找些新证人
So we re-canvass, develop fresh witnesses.
我今天起诉
The case I charge on today
到庭审时证据会倍加充分
Can be twice as strong by the trial date.
一旦定罪...
We get a conviction...
我们就能从小Barksdale 顺藤摸瓜找到大Barksdale...
We roll Little Boy Barksdale into Big Boy Barksdale...
然后我们就回家...
Then we go home...
像老警察一样用百威干杯
Iike good old-fashioned cops and pound some Budweiser.
全都是屁话
This is bullshit!
是McNulty发现了这几件案子的弹道匹配...
It was McNulty who made the ballistics match on these murders...
也是他让我来争取继续调查
And he's telling me to fight this.
他很清楚你的起诉不可行...
He knows you don't have a viable prosecution...
你我都清楚这点
So do you, so do l.
够了
Enough.
听着 我并不欣赏你的窃听线 中尉
Look, I've got no love for your wiretap, Lieutenant.
我每天从运作预算中...
I'm spending $2,000 a day...
抠出2000块来调查这案子
Over the unit operating budget to staff the case.
现在Rawls警长找到一个机会...
Now, Major Rawls here is offering a chance...
通过起诉一宗谋杀案搞定Barksdale
To leverage Barksdale through a murder prosecution.
为什么不干
Why not jump on this?
因为如果Rawls警长是正确的...
Because if Major Rawls is right...
那么一个月后他依然正确
Then he will be just as right a month from now.
如果窃听小组没有成效 他可以起诉手头上所有的案子
If the wire doesn't give us a case, he can charge all the murders he has.
我们毫无损失
We lose nothing.
但如果他错了...
But if he's wrong...
如果不能定罪 又或者 Barksdale那小子不供认...
If he can't convict, or if the Barksdale kid doesn't flip...
那到时做什么都晚了
Then it's too late to do anything else.
Avon Barksdale改变行动模式
Avon Barksdale changes up his pattern,
窃听线也玩完了
And the wiretap dies.
到那个时候...
At that point, there isn't going to be a thing...
无论你 我 还是Rawls
That you, or me, or Rawls here
都将对法官哑口无言
Is gonna be able to say to that judge.
你要见我 警长?
You wanted to see me, Major?
如果McNulty上班时间办私事 让我知道
McNulty does personal business on the clock, I want to know.
他在出勤单上作弊 让我知道
He cheats on a run sheet, I want to know.
他玩任何把戏 让我知道
He runs any kind of game at all, I want to know.
警长 那家伙是个混球...
Major, the man's an asshole...
但他工作心无旁骛
But he doesn't do much other than work.
他纠结于这个案子 就像它是恶性肿瘤
He's got this case in his gut like it's cancer.
他从不做错事?
He does no wrong?
不再喝酒了? 不在当班时喝酒?
Doesn't drink anymore? Doesn't drink on duty?
不酒后驾驶 探员?
Doesn't drink and drive, Detective?
警长...
Major...
这件事你真得帮帮我 Michael
You've got to help me on this, Michael.
谋杀案的逮捕令申请押后了
The murder warrant's on hold.
副局长允许我们再调查一个月
The Deputy gave us another month.
还有 你今天带来的那个人...
Also, whoever that was you brought in here today...
愿意做Gant谋杀案的目击证人
Gave himself up as an eyewitness to the Gant murder.
谁 Omar?
Who? Omar?
Greggs叫我跟你说 她明天早上写好报告
Greggs said to tell you she'd write it up in the morning.
中尉...
Lieutenant...
谢谢
Thanks.
有代价吗?
It cost you?